Matthew Woll Papers 5262
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Matthew Woll Papers
1943-1957
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Woll, Matthew
5262
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
This collection consists of newspaper clippings about the activities of Matthew Woll from 1914 until his death in 1956.
5675100
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 30, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Matthew Woll was born in Luxembourg on January 25, 1860. He moved to Chicago with his parents when he was eleven years old.
In 1906, two years after getting his law degree from Lake Forest University College of Law, Mr. Woll was elected President of the Photo Engravers Union. He served in this capacity until 1929; he then became Vice President of the Photo Engravers and held this position until his death on June 1, 1956.
In 1919 he was elected eighth Vice President of the AFL He worked closely with Samuel Gompers and many observers of the labor movement were surprised when he was not elected to succeed Mr. Gompers as president of the AFL. When the AFL and CIO merged in 1955, he became the first Vice President of the AFL-CIO.
One of his contributions to the labor movement was the Union Labor Life Insurance Co. He was among the first to recognize the need for insurance protection for trade union members. He was prominent in organizing the company and became its first president in 1927. His leadership helped the company to develop into a respected organization in the insurance field.
He served on many labor, civic, political, and cultural committees, including the War Labor Board - World War I, National War Labor Board - World War II, Chairman of the AFL International Relations Committee, Editor of the Photo Engravers' journal, National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor, N.Y.S. Insurance Advisory Board and Director of Sportsmanship Brotherhood. He also wrote one book entitled Labor, Industry and Government.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Woll, Matthew, 1880--1956
5675100
- Newspaper Clippings 1914-1930 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1914-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clippings 1931-1942 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Sketches 1954-1956; Miscellaneous Sportsmanship papers and publications; Newspaper Clippings 1943-1957 (Box 3)
  - Sketches, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    October 6, 1954 and June 2, 1956
  - "Sportsmanship" Volume 1 Number 5 (Published by the Sportsmanship Brotherhood), 1929 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    February 1929
  - Sportsmanship Brotherhood, Incorporated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)